inasp.info 2015-12-27

# INASP - Privacy policy

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. We are committed to protecting your privacy, and information will not usually be disclosed to third parties without your prior consent. 

## Subscribing to email alerts

Subscribing to updates allows you to receive email alerts on all of our updates, publications and news. You may also specify the type of information your wish to receive. We use Mailchimp to manage our mailing lists.

When registering, we require some personal information. You may access and change this information or your preferences at any time.  the information you provide will be stored via Mailchimp and used by INASP for internal statistical analysis only. Our mailing lists and your personal information will not be passed on for use outside of INASP.

For information on the Mailchimp privacy policy, visit their website: <http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

## Subscribed resources registration

When registering to access e-resources, you must first apply for an account. This account is free, but does require some personal information. If the account is approved, you may then register your institution for resources. Your personal information is password protected for security, and you can access and change your details and requirements at any time.  

As this data is stored in the United Kingdom, you have certain rights in British law under the Data Protection Acts 1984 and 1988. In particular, you have the right to be told what personal information we hold about you on our databases.

If you are concerned about how your information is used, we recommend that you review this privacy statement periodically, as INASP may update it from time to time.

If you feel that this site is not following its stated privacy policy, you may contact us at inasp@inasp.info. We will be sure to address your concerns.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small file that contains a unique alphanumeric code selected randomly. This cookie is stored on your computer. Cookies are used, for example, to count the total number of unique users who are accessing a website over a particular period of time, or to see which pages are most frequently viewed.

INASP's website uses cookies to collect data about its activity. Cookies do not identify the person at the computer, and information gathered is not shared with third parties. It is used to monitor the use of the website and provide us with raw data we can use to judge, and demonstrate, the website's effectiveness.

INASP's website uses cookies to collect data about its activity. Cookies do not identify the person at the computer, and information gathered is not shared with third parties. It is used to monitor the use of the website and provide us with raw data we can use to judge, and demonstrate, the website's effectiveness.

### Session cookie

This is used so we can track the user from one page to the next but we are not capturing any details about the user. For example we might use this to keep a collapsible menu in the same state between page requests.

### Authentication cookie

This is used when the user logs in. We place a cookie on their computer that exists for the duration of their browsing the site, and usually until the browser is closed, that indicates that this user is logged in. Without this cookie the user would have to re-enter their login credentials for every restricted page.

## Third party cookies

### Google Analytics

The INASP website makes use of Google Analytics. To learn more about how Google Analytics collects and uses information, see the Google Privacy Center. A 'Browser Opt-out' add-on is available to prevent information being sent to Google Analytics.

### Embed / iFrame content

Where content is embeded from external websites (e.g. in an iFrame, a video from YouTube), you may be presented with cookies from that website. You are therefore advised to check the relevant third party website for more information about those cookies.
